

□ (516) 395-5038 | Salmawanq96@gmail.com | Ohttps://github.com/almawanq | Omwww.linkedin.com/in/alma-wang

Summary __

Current Software Engineer at Two Sigma with a breadth of experiences from working alongside quantitative researchers on a high frequency model simulation environment to building scalable AWS cloud native infrastructure in an internal insurance startup.

Work Experience _

Two Sigma New York, New York

FLOW TRADING ENGINEERING

April 2020 - Present

- · Maintain the Java model simulation environment, research tooling, regression testing and post trading analysis tooling for a Two Sigma tickby-tick variant of high frequency (HF) models that trade a \$25B book.
- · Engineering work for the release and performance monitoring of a new short-horizon trading tactic built on top of existing live trading infrastructure and simulation environment to deliver a projected annual increase of \$0.25M in PnL.
- · Collaborate with quantitative researchers to develop a new model evaluation framework with Beaker notebook friendly Python modules and underlying Java infrastructure used to summarize model performance on dozens of HF models.

MICROSERVICE INFRASTRUCTURE TEAM (WITHIN INSURANCE ENGINEERING)

August 2018 - March 2020

- Cross collaborated with engineering teams to build self-serviceable Terraform-based AWS infrastructure to scale the platform from 5 to over 10+ microservices within Two Sigma's insurance "start-up".
- · Implemented a Kubernetes-based framework for safely running boxed researcher code called by the overall system to expand the company's data science capabilities.
- Drove migration from AWS Elastic Beanstalk to EKS (Kubernetes) with no work by application teams while maintaining complete feature parity.
- Support for and active deprecation of legacy insurance underwriting Java Dropwizard application.
- Built React front-end utilities such as mock JWT token retrieval tool to improve usability of infrastructure teams' work.

HR Engineering - Software Engineering Intern

- · Designed, implemented and released the Candidate Picks App to streamline the company's pre-interview hiring process from multiple hours of resume printing a week to an automated email and interactive front end application.
- · Gathered user requirements by interviewing individuals across the company from Engineering Managing Directors to recruiters.
- Learned and built an Angular 2 + Typescript front end and Guice + Jersey + Jackson + Hibernate Java backend over 10 weeks.
- Implemented demo UI features for the front-end group to expand company usage of Angular 2.

Synopsys (formerly BlackDuck)

Burlington, MA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

January 2017 - March 2017

- Investigated the feasibility of identifying unique software from symbols in the compiled ELF binary executable files to improve the product's security vulnerability scan accuracy.
- Built a Java utility to parse symbols from ELF files and upload to the PostgreSQL DB.
- · Proof of concept work for migration of PostgreSQL to an Atlas graph DB with Apache Hadoop and Spark.
- · Wrote a D3 is based visualization of the data to convey rationale for graph DB migration for the company's Hack Day.

Volunteering

ImpacTS Coding Workshop

New York, New York

GROUP LEAD

January 2019 - March 2019

- Developed and led an Introductory Python course using a Adafruit Circuit Playground (simplified Raspberry Pi) to engage HS students in CS.
- · Organized weekly lessons with students from University Heights High School at Two Sigma offices and with company employees as TAs.

Rewriting the Code

Remote Program

TECHNICAL MENTOR

June 2020 - August 2020

- Mentor and project manager for a group of 5 on the COVID-19 Resources Mobile App Project to promote CS careers amongst college women.
- Guided the group through developing a proof of concept Flutter framework app and demo with weekly sprints over 10 weeks.

Education_

Dartmouth College - GPA 3.84

Hanover NH

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ECONOMICS, MINOR IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS

September 2014 - June 2018

Skills

- Frameworks React, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS
- Languages Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript

MARCH 18, 2021 ALMA WANG · RESUME